<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Temporary Obsessions</title>
    <link>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Temporary Obsessions</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 12:00:33 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
        <atom:link href="https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>What if everyone gets over the bar?</title>
      <link>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/everyone-over-the-bar/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Apr 2018 12:00:33 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/everyone-over-the-bar/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Suppose a school had a basketball team, and the coach of the team worked to challenge every player to be the best they could be. Maybe even better. The players developed skills at all positions, and everyone played. There was no regular, default starting lineup, because the players could be selected at random to form a group of five who could play together, and win games, as a team. The players are excited to be there, they work hard together, and they cheer each other on. And they all get to play.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And they win a lot of their games. Often a championship. Not alwayshttps://gohugo.io/content-management/formats/, but mostly.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;How would we think about that coach? As a genius? Maybe it seems impossible, or that couldn&#39;t possibly the right way to coach. But we probably wouldn&#39;t argue much with the results: a team that works hard, values every player, and wins. What&#39;s bad about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Nothing, of course.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Now, let&#39;s imagine a math teacher at a different school. One who sets a high standard of excellence and challenges every student. One who works exceedingly hard to build a team of math students, who cheer each other on, who help each other learn. At the end of the year, every one of those students scores at the top of whatever standard math assessment is current for the school. And every one of them gets an A.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But wait, we might say. Grade inflation! The teacher is just handing out the top grades. You can&#39;t possibly have a math class where everyone gets an A. Where&#39;s the bell curve? Who is at the top?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Are these cases really that different? The methods seem to be pretty much the same: set a high bar and work like hell to get everyone over it. They do it as a team. They get everyone there, together. And, both cases, we would be happy with the outcome.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Except for this little nagging feeling that everyone getting an A isn&#39;t right.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maybe that&#39;s the problem we have: the feeling that students have to be ranked. That for some to succeed, some must fail.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Which approach actually serves the students better?&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>That great idea I had</title>
      <link>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/that-great-idea-i-had/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Apr 2018 11:22:56 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/that-great-idea-i-had/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This is a post about a great idea I had while I was out for a walk yesterday.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Unfortunately, it&#39;s only &lt;em&gt;about&lt;/em&gt; the idea. I&#39;m not exploring the idea itself.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Because I forgot it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I forgot it in the fewer than ten minutes it took me to get home. Or maybe it was because I was too close to home, and the process of going into the house and talking to my family pushed it out of my mind.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was a pretty good idea. Maybe not an actual great idea, but not bad. Something worth writing about. A little evolution in my thinking on something or other. Or maybe it wasn&#39;t actually that good, and I would have ended up discarding it without writing a word about it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I didn&#39;t write it down. Or ask Siri to remind me about it. Why didn&#39;t I?&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Friction and hubris. Friction, in that it was cold outside yesterday. I had gloves on. As it happened, I did have a notebook and pen in my pocket, but they were hard to get to. The phone was similarly inconvenient. It would have meant standing by the side of the road along an awkward curve, feeling exposed, unsafe, and a bit silly standing there scribbling a note. Hubris, in that I thought it was so good and clear that I would remember it.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ten minutes later, it was gone. My mind had moved on.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It might come back again. Ideas often do. But not always. Sometimes they move on. Maybe the idea will move on to someone else---Elizabeth Gilbert has written about that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;But I do know that more ideas will come. Some not as good, some better. Mostly just different. Or similar.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Next time, I will try harder to capture the idea. But if I don&#39;t, I&#39;ll try to get the one after that.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Who do you want to be?</title>
      <link>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/students-who-do-you-want-to-be/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Apr 2018 11:48:13 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://temporaryobsessions.github.io/posts/students-who-do-you-want-to-be/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;A high school principal I know told a story told to her by another principal. It was approximately:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
A lot of students ask me what it takes to get into the National Honor Society. But one student stood out for asking a different question: &#34;What is it like to &lt;em&gt;be&lt;/em&gt; a member of the National Honor Society?&#34; (emphasis mine)
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This question bounced in my mind off something else I heard recently, on a college tour with one of my daughters. There, one of the admissions officials said something like:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
Most of our students share the following three characteristics (what they were doesn&#39;t really matter). You don&#39;t have to have all three of these, or two of them, or even one. But you should want to be around people like that.
&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For students looking at colleges, or, in fact, for any of us looking at a new job with a new organization, or a new role of any kind, these questions provide a valuable way of thinking about what to do:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the characteristics of the people involved?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does that represent the kind of person I am on my way to becoming?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Does that represent the kind of person I want to be?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Do I want to spend (a lot of) time with people like that?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;If the answer to any of the last three is &#34;no&#34;, then it doesn&#39;t seem like it&#39;s the best place to go, no matter how prestigious, ego-boosting, or monetarily rewarding it may be.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>